LEYTON C. J. REED

SRE / DEVOPS CONTRACTOR

in

uk.linkedin.com/in/leyton



07479 272 800



recruit@zeroclicks.co.uk

PERSONAL PROFILE

I love nothing more than working with infrastructure to provide stable, secure, and scalable solutions to problems and business requirements.

I've spent most of my Linux career in the hosting space, specialising in making websites fast and highly available - working with developers and stakeholders to ensure that expectations are set, met, and that the application works with the infrastructure and can scale on demand.

For a few years, I worked as a PHP developer for SMEs - while writing code is something I thoroughly enjoy, I realised that I prefer working with infrastructure, and transitioned back over to a more DevOps style role where I could write middleware to aid the internal DevOps process.

KEY TECHNOLOGIES

- AWS / Openstack / VMWare
- RHEL / CentOS Linux
- Debian / Ubuntu Linux
- 3PAR and Compellent SANs
- RCHS / PCS clustering
- DRBD / NFS / GFS / RDM
- MySQL replication & Galera
- LEMP / LAMP web stack
- Ansible, Salt & some Puppet
- Haproxy, NGINX, Varnish VCL
- Bash, Python, Golang, PHP, SQL

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

APRIL 2019 - PRESENT: DEVOPS CONSULTANT AT BURBERRY 5 MONTH CONTRACT

- BAU tasks to assist with DevOps backlog and working on their cloud transformation programme to make better use of AWS managed services. We've had a particular focus on security/patch monitoring and automation which previously was in an unknown state.
- Improving processes and architecture of their existing infrastructure for cost optimisation and stability.
- Working to maintain and support current infrastructure within AWS and on-prem, and move towards simplifying their cloud estate and build services out according to best practices.
- Working with stakeholders across the business to ensure other projects dependent on the AWS infrastructure continue to progress while the cloud transformation is being scoped and implemented.
- Ownership over: AWS, GCP (for K8S), PingFederate (SSO), ActiveMQ, ELK, Grafana, GitLab, Jenkins.
- Tooling: Chef, Terraform, CloudFormation, GitLab Cl.
- Stack: RDS, SQS, EKS, Fargate, and lots of EC2 working to move some of the EC2 to managed services.

DECEMBER 2017 - APRIL 2019: ENTERPRISE LINUX / DEVOPS ENGINEER AT UKFAST

- I worked with UKFast's largest clients to provide ongoing support and management of their solutions. I also provide consultation for upgrades to solutions to garner best performance and capacity.
- Internally, I manage our automated blackhole system for DDOS protection. This is deployed with GitLab CI, Docker, and MongoDB. I also built a web interface in Laravel for configuration changes.
- Using the same technologies, I also built a 'queue' system to help overloaded websites that can't scale in GoLang with a management interface in Laravel. This helped several of our SME clients on Black Friday when they were over capacity and unable to scale due to application constraints.
- I also maintained their 24TB ELK stack used for internal logging and analysis, deployed into UKFast's Openstack public cloud using Terraform and Ansible, storage backed by Ceph.
- UKFast has one of the largest Cisco UCS deployments in the UK, and along with HP 3PAR SANs and VMWare, it makes up the eCloud Hybrid and Private cloud products.
- I take part in on-call duties as an escalation point for our nightshift and weekend shift staff.
- UKFast are starting to branch into AWS, so I've been working with clients on migrating their workloads from VMWare into AWS, and will be sitting my AWS SA Associate in April.

OCTOBER 2015 - DECEMBER 2017: SENIOR LINUX ENGINEER AT UKFAST

- UKFast is a managed hosted service provider, operating from its own datacentres in Manchester.
- As a third-line Linux engineer, my day is spent problem solving and resolving issues afflicting client services ranging from simple issues such as debugging mail delivery and advising on best practice, to disaster recovery and substantive repairs to complex solutions.
- I supported servers with control panels (cPanel and Plesk), LAMP and LEMP stack solutions, Magento
 Optimised solutions, and clustered services using the RedHat Cluster Suite & Pacemaker plus DRBD /
 GFS / NFS / Unison file replication.

- In depth knowledge of the Linux operating system, preferring RHEL derivatives, but also comfortable with Debian-based distros.
- Further, I'm also well-versed in the following technologies: Load Balancing with HAProxy and NGINX, caching with Varnish and writing VCL, server orchestration with Ansible, management of virtualised infrastructure running under VMWare and Hyper-V plus experience with Openstack, monitoring services with Zabbix, knowledge of LAMP and LEMP stack deployment and optimisation, complete understanding of DNS, and a working knowledge of SQL-based DBMS'.
- I take part in designing and shaping client solutions to ensure that they fully meet their needs.

AUGUST 2012 - SEPTEMBER 2016: MANAGING DIRECTOR AT IMAGINELAYER (VERSOBIT)

- imagineLayer is a hosted services provider and MSP. My role covered technical support, system administration, system deployment, and budgeting and invoices.
- Deploying and maintaining hosting infrastructures, LEMP stack for hosting, Asterisk for telephony,
 VMWare ESXi for internal systems, OpenVZ and KVM/QEMU for customer VPS.
- Handling small business IT systems and support both onsite and remotely.
- Experience managing Office 365 for clients, as well as management of Google Apps for Business.
- Further to this, though working with VersoBit clients on software development, I have experience working to an agile methodology, and have honed my programming skills.
- Server orchestration using Ansible, however trialled both Puppet and Chef.

JUNE 2012 - JUNE 2013: TECHNICAL SUPPORT (1st/2nd line) AT FORCE 36

 Supporting and troubleshooting software issues, hardware issues, and issues with network services, such as Intermedia's Exchange platform, local MS Exchange, Kerio Connect, IMAP-based email.

QUALIFICATIONS

2019 – 2022: AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate

2013 – 2015: King's College London, University of London

Subject	Level	Grade	Date Achieved
Computer Science with Management	Undergraduate Certificate	Pass	Summer 2015

2011 – 2013: Saffron Walden County High Sixth Form

Subject	Level	Grade Attained	Date Achieved
Business Studies	A Level	Α	Summer 2013
Computing	A Level	В	Summer 2013
English Literature	A Level	В	Summer 2013

2006 – 2011: Saffron Walden County High School

Subject	Level	Grade Attained	Date Achieved
English	GCSE	A*	Winter 2010
AiDA (ICT)	GCSE	Distinction	Summer 2011
CiDA (ICT)	GCSE	Distinction	Summer 2011
English Literature	GCSE	Α	Summer 2011
Science	GCSE	Α	Summer 2011
Additional Science	GCSE	Α	Summer 2011
Mathematics	GCSE	В	Summer 2011
Electronics	GCSE	В	Summer 2011
Citizenship Studies	GCSE	В	Summer 2011
Functional Skills	GCSE	Pass	Winter 2010

REFERENCES

Available on request.